{
  "questions" : [ {
    "id" : 1,
    "question" : "Wie sieht die Signatur der Einstiegs-Methode aus?",
    "answer" : "public static void main(String[] args)",
    "categories" : [ "java" ],
    "choices" : null
  }, {
    "id" : 2,
    "question" : "Wie heißt das keyword für die Objekt Vererbung?",
    "answer" : "extends",
    "categories" : [ "java" ],
    "choices" : [ "inherit", "extends", "implement", "child", "sub" ]
  } ],
  "categories" : [ "java" ],
  "quizzes" : [ {
    "quizId" : 0,
    "questions" : [ {
      "id" : 2,
      "question" : "Wie heißt das keyword für die Objekt Vererbung?",
      "answer" : "extends",
      "categories" : [ "java" ],
      "choices" : [ "inherit", "extends", "implement", "child", "sub" ]
    }, {
      "id" : 1,
      "question" : "Wie sieht die Signatur der Einstiegs-Methode aus?",
      "answer" : "public static void main(String[] args)",
      "categories" : [ "java" ],
      "choices" : null
    } ],
    "category" : "java",
    "answers" : [ ],
    "nextQuestionIdx" : 0
  }, {
    "quizId" : 1,
    "questions" : [ {
      "id" : 1,
      "question" : "Wie sieht die Signatur der Einstiegs-Methode aus?",
      "answer" : "public static void main(String[] args)",
      "categories" : [ "java" ],
      "choices" : null
    }, {
      "id" : 2,
      "question" : "Wie heißt das keyword für die Objekt Vererbung?",
      "answer" : "extends",
      "categories" : [ "java" ],
      "choices" : [ "inherit", "extends", "implement", "child", "sub" ]
    } ],
    "category" : "java",
    "answers" : [ ],
    "nextQuestionIdx" : 0
  }, {
    "quizId" : 2,
    "questions" : [ {
      "id" : 2,
      "question" : "Wie heißt das keyword für die Objekt Vererbung?",
      "answer" : "extends",
      "categories" : [ "java" ],
      "choices" : [ "inherit", "extends", "implement", "child", "sub" ]
    }, {
      "id" : 1,
      "question" : "Wie sieht die Signatur der Einstiegs-Methode aus?",
      "answer" : "public static void main(String[] args)",
      "categories" : [ "java" ],
      "choices" : null
    } ],
    "category" : "java",
    "answers" : [ "extends", "public static void main(String[] args)" ],
    "nextQuestionIdx" : 2
  }, {
    "quizId" : 3,
    "questions" : [ {
      "id" : 2,
      "question" : "Wie heißt das keyword für die Objekt Vererbung?",
      "answer" : "extends",
      "categories" : [ "java" ],
      "choices" : [ "inherit", "extends", "implement", "child", "sub" ]
    }, {
      "id" : 1,
      "question" : "Wie sieht die Signatur der Einstiegs-Methode aus?",
      "answer" : "public static void main(String[] args)",
      "categories" : [ "java" ],
      "choices" : null
    } ],
    "category" : "java",
    "answers" : [ "extends", "weiss ich nicht" ],
    "nextQuestionIdx" : 2
  }, {
    "quizId" : 4,
    "questions" : [ {
      "id" : 1,
      "question" : "Wie sieht die Signatur der Einstiegs-Methode aus?",
      "answer" : "public static void main(String[] args)",
      "categories" : [ "java" ],
      "choices" : null
    }, {
      "id" : 2,
      "question" : "Wie heißt das keyword für die Objekt Vererbung?",
      "answer" : "extends",
      "categories" : [ "java" ],
      "choices" : [ "inherit", "extends", "implement", "child", "sub" ]
    } ],
    "category" : "java",
    "answers" : [ "weiss ich nicht", "weiss ich nicht" ],
    "nextQuestionIdx" : 2
  } ]
}